{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Challah","incorrectAnswers":["Matzo","Bagel","Pita"],"question":"What is the name of the loaf of bread traditionally baked for the Jewish Sabbath?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"\"Bohemian Rhapsody\" by Queen","incorrectAnswers":["\"Let it Be\" by the Beatles","\"SpongeBob SquarePants Theme\" by Painty the Pirate","\"In da Club\" by 50 Cent"],"question":"Which song begins with the lyrics: \"Is this the real life? Is this just fantasy?\"?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Vasily Kandinsky","incorrectAnswers":["James Abbott McNeill Whistler","René Magritte","Pierre-Auguste Renoir"],"question":"Which artist painted \"Composition 8\"","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Kevin Spacey","incorrectAnswers":["Russell Crowe","Jean-Claude Van Damme","John Turturro"],"question":"Which actor has played roles in House of Cards and American Beauty?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Woebegone","incorrectAnswers":["Ratoon","Dragoman","Bobsy-die"],"question":"Which word is defined as 'sad or miserable in appearance'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Southampton","incorrectAnswers":["Cardiff","Portsmouth","Plymouth"],"question":"Where Did The Mayflower Set Sail From In 1620?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Bulgaria","incorrectAnswers":["Guatemala","Cuba","Belgium"],"question":"In which country would you find the Rila Monastery?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"13","incorrectAnswers":["66","666","21"],"question":"How many witches in a coven?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Anders Celsius","incorrectAnswers":["Celso de Gama","Max Gradel","Hoff Zimmerman"],"question":"Who invented the centigrade scale?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Nathaniel Hawthorne","incorrectAnswers":["Robert E. Howard","Henryk Sienkiewicz","Charles Dickens"],"question":"Which author wrote 'A Wonder-Book for Girls and Boys'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Imagine Dragons","incorrectAnswers":["Collective Soul","Three 6 Mafia","The Velvet Underground"],"question":"Which American pop rock band released the song 'Believer'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"The Anaheim Ducks","incorrectAnswers":["The Chicago Blackhawks","The Pittsburgh Penguins","The New York Rangers"],"question":"Which NHL team got its name from a Disney film?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"King John","incorrectAnswers":["King James","King William","King George"],"question":"Which English King issued the Magna Carta in 1215?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Africa","incorrectAnswers":["South America","Oceania","Europe"],"question":"The country of Guinea-Bissau is on which continent?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Brock","incorrectAnswers":["Vince","Erika","Commander Cole"],"question":"Who is the first gym leader you fight in 'Pokémon' for the Game Boy?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Peanuts","incorrectAnswers":["Garfield","Calvin and Hobbes","Dilbert"],"question":"In which comic strip is the insecure boy, Linus van Pelt, found?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Henry II","incorrectAnswers":["William I","Richard III","Henry VIII"],"question":"Who Said \"Will No-One Rid Me Of This Turbulent Priest\"?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"After a girl is uprooted from her life, her emotions conflict on how best to navigate a new life.","incorrectAnswers":["A slacker seeks restitution for a rug ruined by debt collectors.","POWs are forced to build a railway, not knowing that allies are planning to destroy it.","In a post-apocalyptic wasteland, a woman rebels against a tyrannical ruler."],"question":"What is the plot of the movie Inside Out?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Garnet","incorrectAnswers":["Topaz","Amethyst","Ruby"],"question":"What is the birthstone for January?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Singapore Sling ","incorrectAnswers":["Bloody Mary","Mojito","Cosmopolitan"],"question":"Which Famous Cocktail Was Invented At The Raffles Hotel? ","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"L.A. Confidential","incorrectAnswers":["Aliens","Schindler's List","Raging Bull"],"question":"Name the movie that matches the following plot summary: 'Three policemen investigate a series of murders with their own brand of justice.'","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Elton John","incorrectAnswers":["Mika","Madonna","Eric Clapton"],"question":"Which singer released the album 'Goodbye Yellow Brick Road'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"eggs","incorrectAnswers":["organic particles, such as bacteria, fungal spores, very small insects and pollen","genetic differences in relation to the environment","the structure of cells"],"question":"What is Oology the study of?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Ukraine","incorrectAnswers":["Antigua and Barbuda","Equatorial Guinea","Uruguay"],"question":"Which region of the world uses '.ua' at the end of its web addresses?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Mercury","incorrectAnswers":["Jupiter","Venus","Mars"],"question":"Which planet did the Mariner 10 probe take pictures of in 1974?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Eschatology","incorrectAnswers":["Apocology","Epistemology","Tautology"],"question":"In theology, the study of final things such as death, judgement and the end of the world is called:","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Mark Twain","incorrectAnswers":["Charles Dickens","Kurt Vonnegut","Jean Paul Sartre"],"question":"What pen name did the writer Samuel Clemens publish his novels under?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"Carpe diem. Seize the day, boys. Make your lives extraordinary.\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"Listen to them. Children of the night. What music they make.\"","\"Very nice!\"","\"I'll have what she's having.\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film 'Dead Poets Society'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"A Pear tree","incorrectAnswers":["An Oak Tree","A Cherry Tree","A Christmas Tree"],"question":"What tree is mentioned in the Christmas song 'Twelve Days of Christmas' ?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Beatles","incorrectAnswers":["Deep Purple","Feeder","Uriah Heep"],"question":"Which English rock band released the song 'All My Loving'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Impressionism","incorrectAnswers":["Abstract expressionism","Cubism","Dadaism"],"question":"The painting \"Impression, Sunrise\" by Claude Monet is a part of which art movement?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"The Moon","incorrectAnswers":["Mars","Jupiter","Mercury"],"question":"Which of the following is not a planet?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Monica Geller","incorrectAnswers":["Rachel Green","Phoebe Buffay","Janice Hosenstein"],"question":"What is the name of the character played by Courtney Cox on the show 'Friends'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"The Titanic","incorrectAnswers":["The Lusitania","The Victory","The Belfast"],"question":"What was the sister ship of The Olympic?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Concorde","incorrectAnswers":["The Channel Tunnel","Eurostar","An animal cloning plant"],"question":"In 1962, for what did Britain and France sign an agreement to build together?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"China","incorrectAnswers":["Southeast Asia","India","Central Asia"],"question":"Where in the world are pears originally from?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"1431","incorrectAnswers":["1213","1390","1344"],"question":"In Which Year Was Joan Of Arc Burned At The Stake?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Distance","incorrectAnswers":["Time","Brightness","Mass"],"question":"What concept is measured by a light year?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"We're not worthy!  We're not worthy!","incorrectAnswers":["Cowabunga! Cowabunga!","Show me the money!","I'll be back"],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the '90s film Wayne's World?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"France","incorrectAnswers":["Russia","South Africa","Germany"],"question":"Which country hosted the 1998 FIFA World Cup?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Atari","incorrectAnswers":["Sega","Nintendo","Sony"],"question":"What company made the first color arcade game?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Hyundai","incorrectAnswers":["Toyota","Ford","Honda"],"question":"What company owns the motoring brand 'Kia'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Orange","incorrectAnswers":["Gold","Black","Yellow"],"question":"Which of these colors is included on the flag of India?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Gustav Klimt","incorrectAnswers":["‎‎Edvard Munch","Raphael","Leonardo da Vinci"],"question":"Which artist painted \"The Kiss\"","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Aesop","incorrectAnswers":["Homer","Plato","Odysseus"],"question":"Which Ancient Greek writer was famous for his Fables?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Skateboarding","incorrectAnswers":["Surfing","BMX","Skydiving"],"question":"What extreme sport is Tony Hawk known for?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Aegean Airlines","incorrectAnswers":["Olympus Air","Hermes","Hellenic Airways"],"question":"What Is The National Airline Of Greece?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Trampoline","incorrectAnswers":["Golf","Wrestling","Squash"],"question":"What sport was first introduced into the Olympics in 2000?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"G-Type","incorrectAnswers":["Red Dwarf","K-Type","Brown Dwarf"],"question":"What type of star is the sun?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Halloween","incorrectAnswers":["Friday the 13th","Scream","IT"],"question":"Which series of films features a habitual serial killer called Michael Myers","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"2008","incorrectAnswers":["2000","2004","2012"],"question":"When was the first black US President elected?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Red Hot Chili Peppers","incorrectAnswers":["The Monkees","Black Flag","Journey"],"question":"Which American rock band released the album 'Californication'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Reindeer","incorrectAnswers":["A Whale","A Mouse","A Spider"],"question":"What type of animal is a caribou?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Tim Burton","incorrectAnswers":["Steven Spielberg","Woody Allen","Martin Scorsese"],"question":"Which director directed Batman?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Alpha & Omega","incorrectAnswers":["Beta & Gamma","Sigma & Tau","Delta & Epsilon"],"question":"What are the first and last letters of the Greek alphabet?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Somalia","incorrectAnswers":["Niger","Chad","Tunisia"],"question":"Which of these countries occupies the 'horn' of Africa?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Key West","incorrectAnswers":["Key North","East Key","South Key"],"question":"The southernmost point in the 48 mainland American states?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Salma Hayek","incorrectAnswers":["Penelope Cruz","Cameron Diaz","Jennifer Lopez"],"question":"Who was the executive producer of 'Ugly Betty' and also guest starred as Sofia Reyes?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"Well, I don’t want to survive. I want to live.\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"Nobody puts Baby in a corner.\"","\"It's alive! It's alive!\"","\"A martini. Shaken, not stirred.\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film '12 Years a Slave'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Gulf of St. Lawrence","incorrectAnswers":["Hudson Bay","Bay of Fundy","Gulf of Mexico"],"question":"Which body of water is located between Newfoundland and the Canadian mainland?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Honda","incorrectAnswers":["Land Rover","Cadillac","Ford"],"question":"The Civic is a model of car made by which manufacturer?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Secular","incorrectAnswers":["Communist","Feudal","Monarchial"],"question":"Which of these words describes the Indian state?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Hera","incorrectAnswers":["Aphrodite","Athena","Minerva"],"question":"Who was Hercules' stepmother?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Stringed","incorrectAnswers":["Brass","Percussion","Woodwind"],"question":"What type of instrument is a guitar?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Al Dente ","incorrectAnswers":["Bitten","Forza","Allegri"],"question":"What Is The Term Used To Describe Pasta That Is Cooked Correctly?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Son","incorrectAnswers":["Daughter","Brother","Sister"],"question":"Complete the title of this song by the rock band Kansas: \"Carry on Wayward ______”","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"Say hello to my little friend!\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"I’m the guy who does his job. You must be the other guy.\"","\"Snap out of it!\"","\"Tell 'em to go out there with all they got and win just one for the Gipper.\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film 'Scarface'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Wessex","incorrectAnswers":["Cumbria","Yorkshire","Hertford"],"question":"Which of these was a kingdom in Anglo-Saxon England?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Take That","incorrectAnswers":["Talk Talk","Feeder","Bring Me the Horizon"],"question":"Guess The Band From These Initials MO / HD / RW / JO / GB","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"They spread overground","incorrectAnswers":["Underwater","They climb up vertical surfaces","They cling to animals"],"question":"How do procumbent plants grow?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Rolling Stones","incorrectAnswers":["McFly","Delirious?","Depeche Mode"],"question":"Which band includes 'Keith Richards'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Twilight","incorrectAnswers":["Harry Potter","The Hunger Games","The Chronicles of Narnia"],"question":"In which book series does 'Edward Cullen' appear?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Destiny's Child","incorrectAnswers":["MercyMe","Three 6 Mafia","The Velvet Underground"],"question":"Which American rhythm and blues girl group released the studio album 'Destiny Fulfilled'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Jellyfish","incorrectAnswers":["Squid","Shark","Whale"],"question":"Which type of animal are the Sea Wasp and Cubozoa?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Eins","incorrectAnswers":["Één","Um","Zwei"],"question":"What is the German word for 'one'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Peso","incorrectAnswers":["Euro","Dollar","Rand"],"question":"What is the Mexican currency called?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"The Irish","incorrectAnswers":["The Scots","The Welsh","The English"],"question":"Which cultural group has the stereotype of being lucky?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Confucius","incorrectAnswers":["Laozi","Buddha","Sun Tzu"],"question":"Dating from the 5th century B.C., what is the name of the Asian philosopher who wrote 'The Analects'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"G. W. F. Hegel","incorrectAnswers":["William of Ockham","Bertrand Russell","Democritus"],"question":"Which philosopher famously said 'What is rational is actual and what is actual is rational'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Illinois ","incorrectAnswers":["Michigan","Indiana","Ohio"],"question":"In which US state is Chicago","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Brussels","incorrectAnswers":["Antwerp","Ghent","Liège"],"question":"What is the capital of Belgium?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Roger Moore","incorrectAnswers":["Sean Connery","George Lazenby","Timothy Dalton"],"question":"Who played the role of James Bond in The Spy Who Loved Me?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"Who's on first.\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"I am Groot.\"","\"My mother thanks you. My father thanks you. My sister thanks you. And I thank you.\"","\"Hasta la vista, baby.\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film 'The Naughty Nineties'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Sweating","incorrectAnswers":["Boiling","Sautéing","Poaching"],"question":"What cooking method involves softening ingredients over low heat without browning them?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"1929","incorrectAnswers":["1987","2001","2008"],"question":"In what year did the Dow Jones Industrial Average crash and lose 23% of its value in what is known as 'Black Tuesday'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Michael Jackson","incorrectAnswers":["Nicki Minaj","Neil Young","Eric Clapton"],"question":"Which American singer released the song 'You Rock My World'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Shaped pasta","incorrectAnswers":["Soup pasta","Stuffed pasta","Ribbon pasta"],"question":"What type of pasta is strozzapreti?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Mick Jagger","incorrectAnswers":["Elvis Presley","David Bowie","Elton John"],"question":"Which singer starred as the Australian outlaw \"Ned Kelly\" in the 1970 film?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Ford","incorrectAnswers":["Volkswagen","Opel","Land Rover"],"question":"Which car manufacturer makes the Fiesta?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Hans Christian Andersen","incorrectAnswers":["Beatrix Potter","Søren Kierkegaard","Oscar Wilde"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Swineherd'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"It is used in baking to stabilize egg whites.","incorrectAnswers":["It is commonly used as a condiment and food preservative.","It is used in liquid fertilizers, potassium soaps and detergents.","It is used in thermometers, thermostats, barometers"],"question":"What is the chemical potassium hydrogen tartrate often used for?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Bruce Springsteen","incorrectAnswers":["Eric Clapton","Neil Young","Frank Zappa"],"question":"Which American musician released the album 'The River'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Vera","incorrectAnswers":["Shea","Daphne","Mary"],"question":"What was the name of Norm's wife on Cheers?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Pride and Prejudice","incorrectAnswers":["The Fault in Our Stars","Ship of Fools","War and Peace"],"question":"In which book does 'Lady Catherine de Bourgh' appear?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"paso doble","incorrectAnswers":["tango","salsa","ballet"],"question":"What is the name of the 2-step dance music that is often played at bullfights?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Samhain","incorrectAnswers":["All Hallows Eve","Harvest Festival","Thanksgiving"],"question":"Halloween originated from which Pagan festival?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Ron Howard","incorrectAnswers":["Steven Spielberg","Woody Allen","Martin Scorsese"],"question":"Which director directed Solo: A Star Wars Story?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"150 million km","incorrectAnswers":["150 thousand km","150 billion km","150km"],"question":"What is the approximate distance from Earth to the sun?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Émile Zola","incorrectAnswers":["Alphonse Daudet","Anatole France","Charles Dickens"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Les Rougon-Macquart'?","difficulty":"hard"},